In regards to Tae-o's employment,
關於正式錄用泰晤一事
as he has completed his internship successfully,
他順利結束了實習
he will be joining us as an official employee next month.
下月起將正式成為我們公司的員工
Tae-o, congratulations!
泰晤，恭喜你！
That's great!
太好了！
Congratulations! Your employee ID is shining!
恭喜哪！你的員工證真耀眼！
Yes.
是啊
Hm? Doesn't he seem kind of gloomy?
怎麼了？他的情緒好像很低落？
You seem down, Tae-o.
泰晤，你沒什麼精神耶
Oh, not at all.
不，沒有啦
I'm happy too. I look forward to working with you all.
我也很開心，以後請大家多多指教
Do you not like me?
你不喜歡我？
I don't.
對
I'm sorry.
對不起
This is a happy moment, right?
這是值得恭喜的事對吧？
Yeah, probably.
對，大概吧
Well, congratulations! Right?
總而言之，我們要恭喜你！對吧？
Right, guys?
對吧？各位
A business get-together?
商務交流會？
Yes, it's a networking event with angel investors who want to invest in ESG.
對，這次活動是針對 環境、社會和公司治理的投資
It's at Lake Akan, Hokkaido.
地點在北海道的阿寒湖
Hokkaido?! That sounds nice.
北海道？聽起來真不錯
I could really go for some crab.
好想吃螃蟹喔
Motomiya and I will go that day. Nishina and Aihara will come support us.
當天由我與本宮負責 請仁科小姐與相原輔助我們
-Yes. -For real?
-好 -我可以去嗎？
All right!
太好了！
There will be a lot of guests from abroad as well, so can you come too, Tae-o?
這次會有許多國外的來賓 泰晤可以參加嗎？
What? Me?
什麼？我嗎？
Yes.
對
I heard there will be investors from Korea. Is that okay?
聽說有韓國的 投資家會出席，可以吧？
Oh, sure. Please come.
哦，可以，麻煩你了
Okay, I understand.
好，我知道了
Tae-o, it's your first work trip.
泰晤，這是你第一次出差哪
Good luck!
加油！
Good luck.
加油
Did I do it wrong?
我說得不對嗎？
Maybe that's what drove your wife away, Kame.
龜哥，你太太 大概就是討厭你這種地方
Let's wrap it up here.
就這麼決定了
-Yes. -Okay.
-好 -好的
-Keep up the good work. -Thank you.
-再麻煩配合了 -謝謝
A Hokkaido date sounds fun, huh?
你很期待吧？可以去北海道約會耶
It's not like that!
才不是那樣！
Huh? Why is it so tense in here?
怎麼了？氣氛怎麼有點尷尬？
Does that mean you rejected Tae-o?
所以你甩了泰晤？
I guess you could say that.
好像是那樣沒錯
This seriously makes no sense.
我真的搞不懂社長耶
Weren't you going to tell him you like him?
你不是打算跟他告白嗎？
That's true, but…
雖然正如你所說的…
I've always loved you.
我從很久以前就喜歡你了
I was having trouble sorting through my thoughts this time.
我目前還沒整理好思緒
Huh? What do you mean?
什麼意思？我聽不懂耶
Sorry, I don't really know myself…
抱歉，我現在也搞不懂
That explains the tension.
所以氣氛才那麼差啊
Then Hokkaido next week will be…
那麼下週的北海道之旅…
hell.
會像是在地獄吧
What is happening?
到底是怎麼了？
How do you feel about Hanaoka?
侑里小姐，你對花岡先生 有怎樣的感覺？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Is Hanaoka someone special to you?
花岡先生是特別的嗎？
Do you like him?
你喜歡他嗎？
Time to get energized.
能量補給
You haven't been back to Hokkaido since the accident.
自從那起意外發生後 你就沒有去過北海道了
Have a good time.
你要玩得開心喔
It's for work, not vacation.
我又不是去旅行，是去出差
But I wouldn't mind some good food.
不過我至少想吃點美食
What do you want as a souvenir, Dad?
爸爸，你想要什麼伴手禮？
Yuri, honestly, are you a bit scared?
侑里，你心裡其實有點害怕？
Yeah.
對
But it's okay.
可是你不用擔心
It's not like we're going to Kiritappu Cape.
我們不會去霧多布岬
And it's been 12 years.
再說已經過了12年啊
Have some good food,
你就盡情享受美食
see some beautiful sights, and come back in high spirits.
欣賞美景，然後平安回來吧
That's the best souvenir you could bring.
那就是最棒的伴手禮
Sure.
好
Thank you.
謝謝
What?
什麼？
Sorry.
抱歉
The Marioka Department Store asked for a revision of today's press release.
萬里岡百貨聯絡我 希望我修改今天發布的新聞稿
I'm urgently heading to the office.
我現在正趕去公司
That sounds rough.
辛苦你了
We'll be fine here.
不用擔心我們
Okay, got it.
這樣啊，明白了
We'll handle things here.
我們會想辦法的
Feel better.
你多保重
Good morning. What happened?
早安，怎麼了嗎？
Aihara slept wrong and hurt his neck.
相原說他落枕了
He can't come today.
今天無法過來
From just that?
就為了那點小事？
Did something happen?
你那邊呢？
Nishina had a work emergency.
仁科小姐突然有工作要處理
What?
什麼？
That means…
也就是說…
Good morning.
早安
What is it?
怎麼了嗎？
Well…
這個嘛…
Um…
那個…
TANCHO KUSHIRO AIRPORT
（釧路機場）
Is this hell?
像是身處地獄
What is this?
這是怎樣？
Um, excuse me.
那個，這給你
Yeah?
嗯？
Which one would you like?
你要哪一個？
Oh, thanks.
哦，謝謝你
-That's corn soup. -What?
-那是玉米濃湯 -什麼？
No, it's nothing.
不，沒事
Those are red-crowned cranes.
是丹頂鶴呢
They're an endangered species, right?
我記得丹頂鶴是瀕危動物吧？
But they're slowly growing their number.
不過牠們的數量正在逐漸增加
They're also much larger than other wild birds.
在野鳥中，牠們的體型相當大
What were they called?
該怎麼說呢？
Sarurun Kamuy.
“Sarurun kamuy”
Huh?
什麼？
In the Ainu language,
這是阿伊努語
it means god of the Marsh.
意思是“濕原之神”
God?
神？
All right, goodbye.
好的，再見
Want me to take it?
要我幫你拍嗎？
-Could you? -Give it here.
-可以嗎？ -給我吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Okay, here goes.
好，我要拍了
All right.
來
Wait…
等等…
-Motomiya. -What?
-本宮 -什麼事？
Get closer.
靠過去一點
-No, I'll take it alone. -It's okay.
-不，我們沒有要合照 -沒關係啦
Don't worry about it.
別在意
Come on, stand next to him.
好了，快點站過去
All right, this spot is good.
過去一點，站這裡
All right.
好了
Okay, here goes.
來，準備囉
I'm taking it now.
我要拍了
Say cheese.
笑一個
Hey, since we're doing this,
我說啊，難得一起合照
how about a smile?
你們笑得開心一點嘛
Okay? Come on, let's go.
好不好？來，要拍囉
Hurry up.
快點露出微笑
Nice.
很好
Yes, we've arrived!
來，我們終於來到這了！
Hokkaido!
北海道！
I heard there's a famous seafood rice bowl place over there.
聽說那裡有間知名的海鮮蓋飯店
Wow, that sounds delicious.
這樣啊，感覺很美味
Apparently the soup curry over there is also popular.
那邊的湯咖哩好像也很受歡迎
Oh, really?
-是喔，這樣啊 -湯咖哩
Where should we go?
我們要吃什麼？
Which do you want to eat?
侑里小姐，你想吃哪一種？
Hm? Me?
嗯？我嗎？
Well…
我想想…
If we're in Hokkaido, seafood rice bowls are a must.
來北海道就是要吃海鮮蓋飯嘛
Which should we get?
你要選哪一家？
Well, um…
這個嘛…
Soup curry?
湯咖哩？
Seafood rice bowl?
海鮮蓋飯？
Definitely seafood rice bowl.
一定要選海鮮蓋飯
-Which one?
-哪一邊？
I don't know.
我不知道
RAMEN AKAN
（阿寒拉麵）
You were craving ramen?
原來你想吃拉麵啊？
Um, yeah.
對啊，沒錯
I need to be considerate here.
我必須察言觀色才行
-Sit there.
-你坐那裡 -請坐
What?
什麼？
It's okay. Sit by Tae-o.
沒關係，你坐在泰晤旁邊吧
Oh, okay.
哦，好
No, please sit there.
不可以，請坐那裡
Okay.
好
No, it's really fine.
不，真的沒關係
Sit there.
你坐那裡
You can't.
-不可以 -什麼？
Everything all right?
你們還好嗎？
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Sorry.
抱歉
Thanks.
謝謝
Here you go.
來
Our corporate philosophy is
敝公司的經營理念是
addressing environmental issues starting with daily deliciousness and fun.
從每天感受到的 美味與喜悅開始著手環境問題
For our customers to understand such issues through everyday experiences,
為了讓客戶透過 切身經驗理解環境議題
we use cacao husks that are usually disposed to manufacture
敝公司使用本來預定丟棄的 可可豆殼製作與販售巧克力
and sell chocolate, as well as daily necessities, and clothing.
日常用品以及衣物
If you please.
麻煩你了
Hello, I'm Yun Tae-o.
大家好，我是尹泰晤
I'm Tae-o Yun. I'm your interpreter for today.
我是今天的口譯員尹泰晤
Our corporate philosophy is
敝公司的經營理念是
addressing environmental issues starting with daily deliciousness and fun.
從每天感受到的 美味與喜悅開始著手環境問題
-The get-together is tomorrow at 11. -Okay.
-明天十一點開始舉行交流會 -好
I want you to talk to the international guests about our business.
泰晤，麻煩你到時候 跟外國來賓介紹我們的業務
Okay, got it.
好的，明白了
Anything you want to ask me?
你還有什麼想問的嗎？
Is it possible…
那個…
in Japan…
在日本…
people don't like guys that come on too strong?
女性會討厭煩人的男性嗎？
What?
什麼？
It's nothing.
算了，沒事
Wait.
等一下
Um…
那個…
Okay, then.
過來一下
Hey.
我問你喔
As of now, are you and Motomiya…
你現在跟本宮的關係是…
She rejected me.
我被甩了
What?
你說什麼？
Wait, but…
不，可是…
Why?
為什麼？
B-But you two…
因為你們兩個…
I…
我很清楚…
know why.
被甩的理由
Huh?
什麼？
Wait, it's me?
等等，是因為我？
You two have a special relationship.
你們倆的關係非常特別
N-No, we don't. You're wrong.
一點也不特別，你誤會了
But Yuri feels that way.
但侑里小姐是那麼想的
No, there really is nothing between us.
絕對不可能，真的不是你想的關係
What about you then?
花岡先生，你呢？
Huh?
什麼啊？
Do you like Yuri?
你喜歡侑里小姐嗎？
Sorry I'm late.
抱歉，我來晚了
Answer me. Why can't you do that?
請回答我，為什麼不說話？
Tae-o, calm down.
泰晤，冷靜一點
What's the matter?
發生什麼事了？
No, we're just talking about work, right?
沒有啦，我們在談論公事
Come on, let's go now.
來，我們走吧
Come on, Tae-o.
過來，泰晤
I'M JOINING DOLCE &amp; CHOCOLAT.. KYOSHUKU DESU.
（我要在朵契與巧克力工作了 真是過意不去，泰晤）
My heart was broken.
我失戀了
Didn't they like each other?
他們不是兩情相悅嗎？
I thought that was the case.
應該是那樣沒錯
I don't get it either.
我也不清楚原因
I'm worried about him.
我好擔心泰晤啊
Well, he'll be fine.
他不會有事的啦
He still has a chance if they work at the same company.
他們待在同一間公司，泰晤還有機會
But…
可是…
Tae-o, do you want to go to Japan with me?
泰晤，你要不要跟我一起去日本？
No!
不行！
I can't let it go!
果然還是不行！
What?
什麼啊？
He's actually not as strong as he looks.
別看泰晤個性開朗，他其實並不堅強
Contrary to belief…
他比大家所想的…
he's a sensitive boy!
那個男孩內心意外地脆弱啊！
O-Okay…
這樣啊
Please, go convince her immediately!
拜託你了，小野田 盡快說服女方吧！
What?
什麼？
-I'm begging you! -Wait!
-算我求你！ -等一下！
Please!
拜託你了！
What? The doctor?
什麼？博士？
Can we meet urgently? I want to speak with you.
現在有空嗎？我有話想馬上告訴你
He finally took the bait.
他終於上鉤了啊
I-It…
真是…
It's so far.
真是遠呢
Y-Yeah, we should've just grabbed a hotel at Lake Akan.
其實住在阿寒湖的飯店就好了
Jeez, that Aihara.
真是的，相原那個傢伙
Why'd he choose a place so far out?
為什麼要訂這麼遠的民宿啊？
Does he really think this will reduce costs?
他以為這樣可以幫公司減輕開銷嗎？
-Right? -Yeah.
-就是說啊 -是啊
And he even hurt his neck on a day like this.
而且還在這種時候落枕
Yeah, seriously.
對啊，拿他沒辦法
Sorry, it was me.
不好意思，其實是我
What?
什麼？
I made the reservation.
這是我訂的民宿
I see.
是這樣啊
Well, this kind of thing isn't bad once in a while.
不過偶爾住在這種地方也不錯嘛
There's so much nature.
自然景觀豐富
And the view's nice too, right?
風景也美極了，是不是？
-Right? -Y-Yeah.
-是不是？ -對
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Yes?
怎麼了？
Isn't it an inconvenience?
你其實很困擾吧？
What?
什麼？
Having me around.
因為我人在這裡
No, not at all.
沒有啊…
Are you tired, Motomiya?
本宮，你累了吧？
-Yeah. -You know,
-是啊 -我記得…
you've never been good around crowds.
你從以前就討厭人多的地方
-That's right. -Yes.
-沒錯… -嗯
Hanaoka,
花岡先生
you sure know everything
看來你對侑里小姐的一切
when it comes to Yuri.
都十分了解呢
Why is this happening?
為什麼會演變成這樣？
I'm so happy you invited me out, Onoda.
我好高興喔，沒想到你會約我出來
More importantly, what happened?
不說這個了，現在到底是怎麼回事？
What?
什麼？
I'm talking about Tae-o.
我指的是泰晤的事
Why reject someone you like?
明明喜歡他，為什麼要甩掉對方？
Oh, I'm not too sure either.
關於那件事啊，我也不太清楚
What?
什麼意思？
Who else would know better than you?
還有誰會比你更清楚？
Huh? About what?
你這是什麼意思？
You know what I mean.
這還用說嗎？
What?
不會吧？
Hm?
嗯？
So basically, the person Tae-o likes is that boss,
簡單來說，泰晤喜歡的是那位社長
and the one who rejected him is also that boss?
甩掉泰晤的人也是她嗎？
Exactly.
就是這麼一回事
Then you have absolutely nothing to do with Tae-o's--
所以說你跟泰晤的戀情完全…
Absolutely nothing to do with it.
完全沒有關係
Then what did I do all that for?
那我做的一切是為了什麼？
In other words,
也就是說
everything was for no reason?
我之前的行動毫無意義，對吧？
No, I'd say there was…
不，沒那種事吧
a reason for it.
有意義喔
After all, that's how we met.
因為我們兩個
You and me.
因此相遇了嘛
How is that significant?
這有什麼意義嗎？
Anyway, in that case, I'm going back to my research.
總之如果事情是那樣 我要回去做研究了
It seems you've already forgotten, Onoda.
小野田先生，看來你已經忘記了
That fateful Valentine's Day.
情人節那天發生的事
Right, the Linaria…
我記得啊，姬金魚草…
Then why did you give that to me?
那你當時為什麼要送給我？
As for that…
這個嘛…
think about it on your own.
請你好好想一想
What?
什麼？
Think about it until you figure out the reason.
你就仔細想想，直到找出原因
Keep thinking long and hard about me.
請你一直想著我，認真地考慮我的事
AINU: LEARN ABOUT THE KAMUY
（《阿伊努：瞭解神威》）
CHAPTER FIVE: THE KAMUY'S VOICE THE POWER OF OHAINU, HEARING VOICES
（第5章：神威的聲音 能聽到聲音的“Ohainu”之力）
THE POWER OF OHAINU
（“Ohainu”之力）
"Ohainu"?
“Ohainu”？
Interested in Ainu culture?
請問你對阿伊努文化有興趣嗎？
Oh, um…
是啊，請問一下…
What is an ohainu?
“Ohainu”是什麼？
Oh, ohainu is the power to hear the kamuy's voice.
哦，“Ohainu”代表“神威的聲音”
It means you can hear the voice of god.
也就是“聆聽神明之聲的力量”
-The voice of god? -Yes.
-神明之聲？ -對
-Thank you. -No problem.
-謝謝 -不客氣
A SUPERNATURAL POWER HELD BY THOSE WITH STRONG DIVINE POWER
（神力特別強大的人擁有的超能力）
THE POWER BLOOMS WITH NO WARNING
（突然展現出能力）
Dad.
爸爸
I'm sorry.
對不起
No, Yuri.
不對
It's not your fault.
這不是你的錯
I can hear you.
我聽得到…
I can hear your voice, Dad.
我能聽到爸爸的聲音
Your meal will be ready shortly.
晚餐快準備好了
Okay, thank you.
我知道了，謝謝
AINU: LEARN ABOUT THE KAMUY
（《阿伊努：瞭解神威》）
Thank you for today, you two.
今天謝謝兩位
We still have tomorrow,
雖然明天也要上工
but good work so far.
先說聲辛苦了
Good work.
辛苦了
-Yes.
-乾杯
Excuse me.
打擾了
Allow me to start the fire.
我來點火
-Thank you. -Excuse me.
-謝謝你 -不好意思
There we go.
好了
-Enjoy. -Thank you.
-請享用 -謝謝
Um, so…
那個，我想請問一下…
Are you tourists?
各位是來觀光嗎？
Well…
這個嘛…
Work trip.
我們是來出差
Oh, you're here for work?
是喔，三位是來工作的啊？
Sorry, I thought you were friends.
不好意思，我還以為你們是朋友
You seem close in age.
因為年齡看起來相近
Well, yes.
是啊
We're classmates from university.
他是我的大學同學
Wow, since university?
天哪，從大學時就認識？
Now you work together?
現在也一起工作嗎？
You must be like family then.
那就跟家人沒兩樣了呢
Well…
沒有啦…
Or rather, we simply started a company together.
準確來說，我們只是一起創業而已
Started a company? Incredible.
創業嗎？真是了不起
That's no easy feat.
那可不是什麼簡單的事
You two must be bound deeply by fate.
看來兩位也很有緣呢
Have a good time then.
那麼請慢慢享用
Um…
那個…
May I ask something?
可以問一件事嗎？
-Hm?
-嗯？
Well, um…
我想了解一下…
Why did you start this company?
你們為什麼會創立這間公司？
That's because…
那是因為…
When we were in university,
我們讀大學時
I was actually torn on whether I should become a researcher or not.
我很煩惱要不要繼續做研究
I see.
這樣啊
During that time,
花岡在那時對我說
Hanaoka said that environmental issues can be fixed particularly through business.
可以靠商業來解決環境問題
I guess you could say that was the trigger.
那可以說是我創立這間公司的契機吧
I knew it.
果然沒錯
You're special to each other.
你們兩個的關係很特別
What?
什麼？
No, I…
不，那個…
But it's not me.
不過我不是那個人
What?
什麼？
The one Motomiya needs…
本宮需要的人…
isn't me.
並不是我
Hanaoka?
花岡？
It's not me.
不是我
My bad.
對不起啦
Really, it's my bad.
我想真心道歉，對不起啦
Again?
又來了？
Oh, no.
天哪，糟糕
But you only had tea.
可是你只有喝茶啊
Huh?
奇怪？
Excuse me, is there alcohol in this food?
-不好意思 -是
Sake steamed scallops and salmon miso soup.
這些是清酒蒸扇貝與石狩鍋喔
Both of them use plenty of Kushiro's local sake.
兩道都使用大量釧路產的酒
Sorry, Hanaoka.
不好意思，花岡先生
-Are you okay? -Hanaoka?
-你還好嗎？ -花岡？
-Is he perhaps allergic? -It's fine.
-難道他對酒精過敏嗎？ -不用擔心…
-Are you okay? I'm sorry! -Don't sleep here.
-不要緊嗎？ -花岡，不要睡在這裡
-Jeez! -I can never get used to this.
-我的天啊！ -不管看過幾次都還是無法習慣
-Hey! -My bad.
-喂！ -對不起啦
Tae-o.
泰晤
My bad.
對不起啦
Please go to sleep.
請你睡吧
I'll bring some water.
我去拿水過來
Thanks.
謝謝
Of course.
不會
My bad.
對不起啦
It's my fault.
這都是我的錯
I just…
我就只是…
want things to go well between you two.
希望你們能順利交往而已
Otherwise, I…
不然我會…
My bad.
對不起啦
I'm back.
我回來了
Welcome back, Onoda. How was it?
你回來啦，小野田，怎麼樣？
Did you convince her?
你有順利說服對方嗎？
It was a misunderstanding.
那件事其實是誤會了
Bravo! That's great.
好極了！那就好
No, it was my misunderstanding.
不是啦，是我誤會了
-What? -The person Tae-o likes isn't Mahiro.
-什麼？ -泰晤喜歡的人不是真尋小姐
Then who in the world…
那他到底喜歡誰？
It's the company CEO.
對方好像是公司的社長
The CEO…
社長…
What? The CEO?
你說什麼？社長？
But don't worry.
不過請你放心
According to Mahiro, the CEO likes Tae-o too.
真尋小姐說社長也對泰晤有意思
Is that true?
真的嗎？
Is that information accurate?
這是正確的情報嗎？
I'm sure of it.
應該沒有錯
The CEO…
社長…
TWO TOURISTS INJURED
（兩名遊客受傷）
I just…
我就只是…
want things to go well between you two.
希望你們能順利交往而已
You're still up.
你還沒睡啊
Yes.
對
Are you having trouble sleeping too?
侑里小姐，你也睡不著嗎？
Yeah, a little.
是啊，有點失眠
Would you…
不介意的話
like to look with me?
要一起看嗎？
What?
什麼？
Sure.
好
Oh, here.
啊，給你蓋
But Tae-o, you…
但是泰晤…
Did you know?
你知道嗎？
Sea otters have the most fur on Earth.
海獺是地球上毛最多的生物
I see.
這樣啊
Each one has 800 million hairs.
一隻海獺有八億根毛
That's cool.
好多喔
I'm also good at withstanding the cold.
我這個人也不怕冷
Don't misunderstand.
不過請你不要誤會喔
that I have a lot of hair.
這不代表我的毛很多
Thanks.
謝謝
It's pretty.
真漂亮呢
Yes.
是啊
It's very pretty.
非常美麗
Sorry.
不好意思
I thought it'd be prettier lying down.
因為我想說躺下來看，星星會更漂亮
You're right.
真的耶
It's prettier this way.
星星看起來更美了
You'll catch a cold.
這樣會感冒喔
Tae-o.
泰晤
Let's share the blanket.
一起蓋毯子吧
Thank you.
謝謝
-Oh, it's a shooting star! -What?
-天哪，是流星！ -什麼？
Oh, um…
哦，就是那個…
The star…
星星…
Oh.
我懂了
-A shooting star? -Yes.
-是指流星？ -對
-Right. -Wow, I wish I could've seen it.
-沒錯 -是喔，真想看流星
Do you make wishes in Korea too?
韓國人看到流星也會許願嗎？
Yes, we do.
會啊，也會許願
Do you have a wish, Yuri?
侑里小姐，你有什麼心願嗎？
What?
我嗎？
I'm not sure.
我也不知道
Do I?
我有心願嗎？
Try saying one.
告訴我吧
I'll make it come true.
我來幫你實現
Isn't that the shooting star's job?
這樣就跟流星無關了吧？
Tae-o,
泰晤，你呢？有什麼心願嗎？
I do.
有啊
What is it?
是什麼？
If I tell you,
如果我跟你說
will you grant it?
你會幫我實現嗎？
Oh, I'm sorry.
啊，對不起
You've already rejected me.
你早就已經甩掉我了
I can't get between you two.
我沒辦法介入你們之間
I know that.
我很清楚這一點
Shall we head back now?
我們差不多該回去了吧
Wait.
等等
Um…
那個…
Stop doing this already.
別再這樣做了
Please…
請你…
stop leading me on.
不要再戲弄我了
I no longer have…
我現在已經對你…
feelings for you.
沒感覺了
I'm sorry.
對不起
We have a Korean person too.
我們的員工也有韓國人
Tae-o, a moment?
泰晤，可以過來一下嗎？
Yes.
好的
He's Yun, one of our employees.
他是我們的員工，姓尹
He researched animals at university.
之前在大學研究動物
This is Min, a Korean investor.
這位是來自韓國的投資人，閔小姐
Can we talk, Hanaoka?
花岡，可以來一下嗎？
Okay.
好
-Sorry, I'll be right back. -Sure.
-不好意思，我離開一下 -好
Hello, I'm Yun Tae-o from Dolce &amp; Chocolat..
你好，我是朵契與巧克力的尹泰晤
Yes, hello.
好的，你好
Nice to meet you.
請多多指教
MIN HA-NA
（閔荷娜）
Min Ha-na?
“閔荷娜”？
Huh?
嗯？
Nuna.
大姐姐
Good work. Will we be on time for our flight?
辛苦了，應該可以 趕得上飛機的時間吧？
Yeah.
可以
Huh?
怪了
Tae-o said he's not going home today.
泰晤說他今天不會回家
What?
什麼？
Apparently, he's going to Kiritappu Cape.
他好像打算去霧多布岬
Kiritappu?
霧多布？
He said he's going to see sea otters.
他說要去看海獺
Sea otters. I see.
是喔，海獺啊
Since we're doing this, how about a smile?
難得一起合照 你們笑得開心一點嘛，好不好？
It'll energize you.
給你能量補給
Here.
請享用
Yuri,
侑里小姐
you're special to me.
是特別的人
Yaksok.
“Yaksok”
It's gotten romantic now, hasn't it?
氣氛浪漫起來了，對吧？
How about me?
那我呢？
Do you like me?
你喜歡我嗎？
Hey…
我說啊…
Hanaoka.
花岡
-I… -No need to say it.
-我… -不用說出口
I can tell either way.
就算你不說，我也知道
Head over
你去找泰晤吧
But…
不過…
Then let's decide with rock-paper-scissors.
那乾脆用猜拳來決定吧
What?
什麼？
If I win,
如果我贏了
you'll go to Kiritappu Cape.
你就去霧多布岬
Be serious.
那算什麼嘛
And you're even not good at rock-paper-scissors.
再說你猜拳老是輸啊
Yeah.
沒錯
That's why,
所以說呢
if I still happen to win,
如果老是在輸的我 現在有辦法贏過你
just go.
你就去吧
Rock, paper…
剪刀、石頭…
scissors…
布…
Here's your shrimp bread.
這是給你的蝦子麵包
Oh, thanks.
哦，謝啦
What about you?
你的呢？
That was the last one.
那是最後一個
Then let's decide who gets to eat it with rock-paper-scissors.
什麼？那我們用猜拳來決定 誰能吃這個蝦子麵包吧
I'm fine.
我不用吃啦
No, I want the decision to be fair.
不可以，我想要公平地做決定
Okay.
好
Let's do it.
開始吧
-Rock, paper, scissors…
-剪刀、石頭…
shoot!
布！
-Hooray! -Aw, man.
-好耶！ -天哪，討厭
Well, I'll just dig right in then.
那我就不客氣了
But you know, Hanaoka,
話說回來，花岡你啊
you're so bad at rock-paper-scissors.
真的很不擅長猜拳耶
You're just good at it.
是因為你太強了啦
Scissors…
剪刀、石頭…
shoot.
布
How?
怎麼會？
Go, Motomiya.
你就去吧，本宮
It's fine. Just go.
不要緊，總之去找他吧
Come on, hurry up.
快點啊，去吧
Thank you, Hanaoka.
謝謝你，花岡
Thank you.
真的很感謝你
I've been with you all these years. Of course I know.
可別小看和你相處了好幾年的我
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Yuri?
侑里小姐？
Tae-o.
泰晤
Why are you here?
侑里小姐，你怎麼來了？
I came to see you, Tae-o.
我是來見你的，泰晤
Why?
為什麼？
I can't go back like this.
我不能就這麼回去
Because…
因為…
I haven't told you how I feel at all.
我還沒有表達出自己的心意！
Yuri…
侑里小姐…
To be honest, I…
我其實…
I actually…
老實說，我…
Yuri!
侑里小姐！
Do you like rice?
你喜歡吃米飯對嗎？
Yes, I do.
對，我喜歡米飯
Do you like curry?
你喜歡咖哩嗎？
I do.
我很喜歡咖哩
Do you like fried rice?
喜歡炒飯嗎？
I like fried rice too.
我也喜歡炒飯
Do you like omurice?
喜歡蛋包飯嗎？
I like omurice too.
也喜歡蛋包飯
What about me?
那我呢？
I like you too!
我也喜歡你！
I like you, Tae-o!
我喜歡上你了，泰晤！
I love you!
最喜歡了！
I like you too!
我也喜歡你！
I love you a lot!
我很愛你！
INNER THOUGHTS, AUDIBLE, LEFT EAR
（心聲、聽得見、左耳）
CAUSES AND CURES FOR AUDITORY HALLUCINATIONS
（幻聽症狀的原因與解決方法）
KOREAN LANGUAGE
（韓語）
INNER THOUGHTS, AUDIBLE, GIRL
（心聲、聽得見、少女）
I found it.
我找到了
Subtitle translation by: Chul Woong Kim
字幕翻譯：劉哲琪
The daruma fell over.
一、二、三，木頭人！
Hot springs? Right now?
現在去泡溫泉？
I can hear other people's thoughts.
我能夠聽到別人內心的想法
I forgot the potatoes.
我忘記馬鈴薯了